Welcome back!
欢迎回来!
Let's now, jump right in.
让我们现在，直接跳进去。
One of the first things that you'd need to understand is, functional programming is a paradigm shift.
你需要了解的第一件事是，函数式编程是一种范式转变。
What do I mean by a paradigm shift?
我说的范式转变是什么意思？
It means that you would need to change how you'd think about problem-solving,
它意味着你需要改变你对解决问题的思考方式、
to master functional programming. And we are here to help you make that transition. In this course,
来掌握函数式编程。而我们在这里就是要帮助你实现这一转变。在这个课程中、
we'll take a step-by-step approach to introduce functional programming to you.
我们将采取循序渐进的方式，向你介绍函数式编程。
In this first section, we start with two key objectives.
在这第一节中，我们从两个关键目标开始。
Number one, is to help you understand how functional programming is different.
第一，帮助你了解函数式编程有什么不同。
Number two, is to help you understand a few basic functional programming concepts.
第二，帮助你理解一些基本的函数式编程概念。
We'll talk about Streams,
我们将讨论流、
we will talk about Lambda Expressions, and we will talk about something called Method References.
我们将讨论Lambda表达式，我们将讨论一个叫做方法引用的东西。
As usual, we'll take a very very hands-on approach towards learning functional programming.
像往常一样，我们将采取非常非常实用的方法来学习函数式编程。
We'll write a few examples in traditional approach,
我们将用传统的方法写几个例子、
and look at, how you can write similar code in functional programming.
并看看你如何在函数式编程中写出类似的代码。
Let's quickly get started.
让我们迅速开始吧。
Creating a new project and starting to write some code. I'm going to create a new project.
创建一个新的项目并开始写一些代码。我将创建一个新的项目。
I have Eclipse open.
我已经打开了Eclipse。
I've already chosen a workspace.
我已经选择了一个工作区。
I would want to create a new project.
我想创建一个新的项目。
So, let's go ahead and create a new Java Project, that's what we'd want to create.
所以，让我们继续前进，创建一个新的Java项目，这就是我们想要创建的东西。
File new, Java Project, and let's give the project a name.
文件新建，Java项目，让我们给这个项目起个名字。
I'll just call this, functional-programming-with-java. As you can see in here, I'm using Java 9.
我就叫它，functional-programming-with-java。正如你在这里看到的，我使用的是Java 9。
Any version of Java greater than 9, is cool. So, Java 9, 10, 11,12; the code which we write in
任何大于9的Java版本，都是很酷的。所以，Java 9、10、11、12；我们在本课程中写的代码
this course is compatible with all the versions. That's the only thing you'd need to do.
本课程所写的代码与所有的版本都是兼容的。这是你唯一需要做的事情。
And after that you can say, Finish.
之后你就可以说，完成。
Now, the project is created for us.
现在，这个项目已经为我们创建。
We have a source folder, where we can write our source code.
我们有一个源文件夹，在那里我们可以写我们的源代码。
Let's get started with creating our first example.
让我们开始创建我们的第一个例子。
The first problem that we would want to solve is, we would want to print a set of numbers.
我们想解决的第一个问题是，我们想打印一组数字。
So, we'll have a list of numbers, and we would want to actually print
所以，我们将有一个数字列表，我们想实际打印出
each element in that list, one by one on a separate line.
列表中的每个元素，一个接一个地打印在一个单独的行上。
Now, how do we do that in a traditional approach?
现在，我们如何用传统的方法来做这件事呢？
Let's quickly look at it.
让我们快速看一下。
I'll Create a new Java class. So, I'll say, new class and I would want to give it a name of, FP01.
我将创建一个新的Java类。所以，我会说，新的类，我想给它一个名字，FP01。
So, we would use Functional Programming 01, is where we are in right now and I'll class this, Structured.
所以，我们将使用功能编程01，这是我们现在所处的位置，我将把它归类为，结构化。
So, FP Structured, is the name of the class and the package name I would give it as, programming.
所以，FP Structured是这个类的名字，我给它的包名是：编程。
Let's add in a main method and let's click, Finish.
让我们添加一个主方法，然后点击 "完成"。
This would create the class for us with the main method, which is present in here, and over here I can
这将为我们创建一个带有主方法的类，它就在这里，在这里我可以
write all the code that we would want.
写下我们想要的所有代码。
So, what do we want to do? We would want to write a method to printAllNumbersInList.
那么，我们要做什么呢？我们想写一个方法来打印AllNumbersInList。
And which approach do you want to use?
你想用哪种方法呢？
We'd want to use a Structured approach, which is the traditional programming approach. Structured approach.
我们想使用结构化方法，也就是传统的编程方法。结构化的方法。
What do we want to print?
我们想打印什么？
We'd want to print, a list of numbers.
我们想打印，一个数字列表。
How do we create a list of numbers?
我们如何创建一个数字的列表？
I can say, List.of. Let's enter a sequence of numbers.
我可以说，List.of。让我们输入一个数字的序列。
This can be random numbers.
这可以是随机数字。
So, let's enter 12, 9, 13, 4, 6, 2, 4,.
所以，让我们输入12，9，13，4，6，2，4，。
Let's have a few duplicates as well, so 12, 15.
让我们也有一些重复的数字，所以12，15。
Let's have a set of numbers in here.
让我们在这里有一组数字。
Now, it's first giving me a compilation errors on the list.
现在，它首先在列表上给我一个编译错误。
Why?
为什么？
Because I've not really imported it in. So, I would want to use java.util.List;
因为我没有真正把它导入。所以，我想使用java.util.List；
So, over here you can see that it's now imported in, java.util.List.
所以，在这里你可以看到，它现在已经被导入了，java.util.List。
I just needed to do Ctrl 1 or Command 1,
我只需按下Ctrl 1或Command 1、
and take the option to import, java.util.List.
并选择导入 java.util.List。
Aha! The method does not really exist right?
啊哈，这个方法其实并不存在，对吗？
Let's try and create the method right now. Ctrl 1 or Command 1,
让我们试着现在就创建这个方法。Ctrl 1或Command 1、
and it says, create the method. Please do create the method for me. Cool! The method is now created for
它说，创建方法。请为我创建这个方法。很好! 该方法现在已经为
us. You can say it's private static void printAllNumbersInListStructured, and I'll want to give a
我们创建了。你可以说它是私有的静态void printAllNumbersInListStructured，我想在这里给一个
name over here. I would want to call this, numbers. And I'll remove this line Ctrl D, Command D; and over here I'd
名称。我想把它叫做 "数字"。我将删除这一行Ctrl D，Command D；在这里我想
want to print all the numbers in the list. Now, you can write the program by yourself. How do you write
想打印列表中的所有数字。现在，你可以自己写这个程序。你怎么写
it? The first thing that we'd need to think about is, how to loop the numbers?
怎么写？我们需要考虑的第一件事是，如何对数字进行循环？
That's the traditional approach, right? So, we would want to first figure out, how do you loop all the numbers.
这就是传统的方法，对吗？所以，我们首先要想清楚，你如何循环所有的数字。
And once you decide how to loop, you can take each of the individual numbers and print it.
一旦你决定了如何循环，你就可以把每个单独的数字打印出来。
So, we'll first choose between, okay
所以，我们首先要选择，好的
should I use a traditional For loop or should I go for enhanced For loop?
我应该使用传统的For循环还是应该使用增强型For循环？
Let's use the enhanced For loop. I'll say, for int number in numbers.
让我们使用增强型For循环。我会说，for int number in numbers.
What do you want to do?
你想做什么？
We'd want to print them out. So, sysout, and number.
我们想把它们打印出来。所以，sysout，和number。
Is that what we'd want to loop?
这就是我们要的循环吗？
So, we'd want to print all the numbers in lists, in a structured way.
所以，我们想以一种结构化的方式打印所有的数字。
All that we needed to do was to loop the list of numbers and print them out.
我们所需要做的就是把数字列表循环起来，然后把它们打印出来。
Let's run this and see what would happen.
让我们运行这个，看看会发生什么。
Right click, Run As, Java Application. Cool!
右键单击，以运行方式运行，Java应用程序。酷！你可以看到现在所有的东西都被打印出来了！
You can see that everything is now printed out to the console.
你可以看到，现在所有的东西都被打印到了控制台。
As you can see in here in the traditional approach,
正如你在这里看到的，在传统的方法中、
whenever we would want to solve a problem, we focus on the how.
每当我们想解决一个问题时，我们都会关注如何解决。
The first thing we needed to do was, okay,
我们需要做的第一件事是，好的、
I have a list of numbers.
我有一个数字列表。
How do I loop around them?
我如何围绕它们进行循环？
Okay, I'll use a For loop.
好的，我将使用一个For循环。
That's the first thing that we did, when we were talking about the Structured approach.
这就是我们在讨论结构化方法时做的第一件事。
Now, how do we solve the same thing in a functional approach?
现在，我们如何用函数式方法解决同样的问题？
I'll keep you guessing.
我让你猜猜看。
Let's see that in the next step.
让我们在下一个步骤中看看。
Until then bye-bye.
在那之前，拜拜。